DC Films Presents Dawn of the Justice League is a
documentary film directed by Eric Matthies.
A documentary special taking a look at the upcoming
films making up the DC Universe.
Kevin Smith hosts with Geoff Johns, as they take a look at Batman vs Superman: Dawn of
Justice, Suicide Squad, the upcoming Wonder Woman and Justice League movies.
Self, played by Henry Cavill.
Self, played by Ray Fisher.
Self, played by David Ayer.
Self, played by Joel Kinnaman.
Self, played by Will Smith.
Self - Host, played by Kevin Smith.
The DC Extended Universe (DCEU) is an American media franchise and shared universe
centered on a series of superhero films distributed by Warner Bros.
It is based on characters that appear in American
comic books published by DC Comics.
The DCEU also includes comic books, short films, novels, and video games.
Like the original DC Universe in comic books, the DCEU is established by
crossing over common plot elements, settings, cast, and characters.
Warner Bros.
began trying to bring various DC Comics superheroes together in films in 2002, when Wolfgang
Petersen was to direct a crossover of the Superman and Batman film franchises.
A planned Justice League film was put on hold in 2008.
Initial universe plans were scrapped after the 2011 film Green
Lantern was a critical and commercial failure.
Warner Bros.
finally established its shared universe with the 2013 film Man of
Steel and 2016's Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice.
This was followed by 13 films and the first season of
Peacemaker, a television series for HBO Max.
The DCEU's 15th and final film, Aquaman and the
Lost Kingdom, was released in 2023.
The DCEU is the ninth-highest-grossing film franchise and the fifth-highest-grossing superhero
film franchise, having grossed more than $7 billion at the global box office.
The highest-grossing DC Comics–based film is Aquaman (2018), which earned more than $1.15 billion worldwide, while
several of the franchise's films failed to break even theatrically, being considered box-office bombs.
Reception to the franchise was generally mixed among critics and fans.
A new rebooted franchise of films and television series, the DC Universe (DCU), was released in 2024 and was created by James
Gunn and Peter Safran, who were appointed co-chairmen and co-CEOs of DC Studios in a late-2022 restructuring.
Certain DCEU characters, such as Peacemaker, Amanda Waller, and Blue Beetle, are played by the same
actors in the DCU, while the second season of Peacemaker takes place in the new universe.
The film explores themes of cyborg, superhero,
interview, based on comic, behind the scenes.